Who goes there?!
Goodness!
Lady Roxy?
You scared me.
Sorry...
You look so different than
you normally do that I didn't realize.
Um... are you heading to the castle like that?
Well, you've already seen me,
so I may as well tell you.
The truth is...
I'm going into town on a secret inspection.
That explains the disguise.
Don't tell anyone, though!
If Haru were to find out...
Milady, please present yourself in a fashion
befitting the head of the Hart family.
Understood!
Very good.
Sorry for delaying you.
I'll get back to work.
Wait a moment, Fay! I've had a great idea.
I'm assigning you a top-secret mission.
You will accompany me during
the inspection, as my escort.
Fay! Hurry along, now!
Right this way! Come on!
Roxy's Inspection
Slow down, Lady Roxy!
Hey, man, if you call her that,
people will notice.
Stop right there!
People will notice if you call me Roxy.
See what I mean?
Shut up!
Excuse me?
No, never mind me.
Let me think...
Why don't you call me "Lexie"?
That's who I am today!
You just thought, "That's not
much of a reach" didn't you?
I said shut up!
Forgive me for being so annoying.
That's not it!
But you just said...
You're not being annoying at all!
Well, all right, then.
I think I was a bit excited at
the thought of us heading out together.
Right.
Ah, to be young.
Seriously, pipe down!
Stop right there!
I won't allow you to treat
your weapon so roughly.
That's a holy knight for you. She gets it.
I'm sorry.
Come to think of it, I've never had
a good look at your sword before.
Not good...
Someone with a worthless skill like mine
wouldn't normally have a sword.
She might think it's weird.
Not to mention...
Once the Gluttony skill gets a taste
of souls, there's no stopping it.
The more you devour, the stronger you get,
and the more you devour, the more you want.
And... if I don't?
You'll starve to death...
or lose control and start
attacking anyone in your path.
I can't let her learn about my Gluttony skill.
I'm sorry.
I'd like to see your sword, Fay.
This is...
It could do with some maintenance.
I'll show you to the Hart
family's blacksmith later.
Thank you.
Come on, let's be on our way.
Right.
Good for you. You're finally
gonna have someone polish you up.
Greed? What's wrong?
Shut up!
I'm basking in the moment. Don't ruin it.
What moment?
Roxy sure does smell nice...
Maybe I oughta throw you around after all!
Fay!
Hurry, now!
Right!
What wonderful grapes.
You've got quite the eye, miss!
These are grapes fresh from
the Hart family vineyard, this morning.
Might I try one?
Well, shucks...
Here.
Thank you.
Fantastic!
Of course. These grapes were
grown at home, after all.
At home?
Oh, no, he's gonna realize
that she's Lady Roxy.
A relative of hers works
for the Harts, remember?
That's it!
One of her relatives works
for the Hart family, actually.
So... y'know.
Oh, that's what you meant!
How much for this?
Oh, that's...
That was incredible, Fay!
Well...
You owe me one, Fate.
I know.
You do?
Oh, just talking to myself.
You're so silly, Fay.
The holy knights are coming!
All the way here in the market?
What's this all about?
Ever since Sir Mason died...
Even the lowest of them
has become unbearable.
Good timing with that one.
Shut up!
Who made that noise?!
What a nightmare...
Was it you?
My apologies, sir.
I can't hear you.
My apologies, sir!
I still can't hear you!
Stop that!
He's already apologized.
Who's this reckless girl that
dares to talk back to a holy knight?
Have I seen you somewhere before?
Isn't that Lady Roxy?
Lady Roxy?
Out here?
This is bad... she's gonna get found out.
Pretend to be lovers. Get real clingy,
and no one will think it's Lady Roxy.
P-Pretend to be lovers?!
Great idea, Fay!
A-And after I made breakfast for you...
Why didn't you eat it?
It just... seemed too good to eat.
Wh-What are you saying?! That's ridiculous!
Sorry.
If you won't eat it,
don't expect me to make it again!
I'll eat! I promise!
So, make it again...
Please?
Yeah, this is getting awkward.
I'll make sure he eats next time.
I beg your pardon.
Come on, let's move along.
Well, that couldn't be Lady Roxy.
No way a holy knight knows how to cook.
We should be all right now.
I've never linked arms with a boy before...
My heart is still racing.
S-Sorry about that!
N-No, it's completely all right.
I'm used to it.
We should really get moving. Let's go!
Ah, to be young.
I think escorting Lady Roxy
might be a bit too tough for me.
Did something catch your eye?
Gems?
Yes.
I am a girl, after all.
Of course I'm interested in them.
Are these gems as well?
That'd be ore.
There's no telling if there's
a gem inside until you crack it open.
Ore...
They're ten bronze coins a piece.
Care to test your luck?
Identify will help you
find a winner at a glance.
That one's a dud.
Watch yourself, though. Merchants tend to
hate people who can use Identify.
It's beautiful.
Looking at her like this, she seems
like a normal girl, not a holy knight.
I'll give you a discount if you wanna
get a present for your girl here.
How's one silver coin sound?
My girl?!
So youthful.
Thank you for letting me see it.
You don't want it?
I've just got no use for it.
Are you sure?
Yes. But I'm wondering, do you
have any warrior acquaintances, Fay?
Aren't Oliver and Minerva warriors?
I have some questions for active
warriors, not retired ones.
About what?
You hear about all those dead goblins?
Yeah. The loudest rumor is that
it's a wandering monster that did it.
That's what people think?
How's that explain that orphanage in the slums
that had goblin king ears donated to it?
The sisters are looking for
whoever donated them, right?
Could you please tell me more about that?
Is there anything else you know
about the roaming monster?
Not really.
You'd be better off asking some warriors.
Fay, can you take me to
where warriors gather?
Um... Is this what your
inspection is really about?
Correct.
I'm investigating the wandering monster
said to appear around the capital lately.
The wandering monster...?
That's me!
Now this is an interesting twist.
Welcome.
Oh, you can't sit there.
It's where a regular of mine
who passed away used to...
Fate?! You're alive?
I am.
Mind if I sit here?
Go ahead!
This is Lexie, barkeep.
She's, uh... a coworker of mine
from my new job.
I'm Lexie. It's a pleasure to meet you.
I hope you'll look after Fate.
Gotta say, you show up after all this time...
And with a girlfriend in tow. Nicely done.
I-It's not like that!
My girlfriend... what if
Lady Roxy gets offended?
Might have you executed for it.
F-Forgive me...
Don't let it bother you.
We get a few warriors who are bad
at controlling their stats
and end up smashing cups.
Nah, I bet she was feeling
self-conscious around you.
Good for you. This just proves
how high your stats have gotten.
And that one was on its last legs.
That makes sense!
I've heard about a warrior who made
a killing off of goblin corpses.
He went out hunting,
and found a mountain of goblin
corpses with their ears still intact.
But a warrior would seek to
cash in on the bounties...
So, if it's not that...
then maybe it really is a wandering monster
that has migrated from another region.
That'll be bad for business, if true.
Why?
Whether you're headed out for stock
or going to the capital to sell...
You have to pass through the goblin plains.
But if there's some mysterious creature
on the prowl, people won't wanna travel.
No one wants to die, after all.
I get it. And it's because of me...
Hey.
Old Ad!
It's good to see you again. It's me, Fate.
A g-g-ghost!
A lich?
Yeah. The popular theory is
the roaming monster is a lich.
That'd be quite the threat, if true.
Yeah. Which is why the holy knights will be
taking direct action to deal with it.
Is that true?
Yeah. A warrior friend of mine
told me about it, so it's certain.
You mean to tell me
we're dealing with holy knights?
With your stats freshly drained,
you'd be done for.
It's more than that.
What's got you so curious about
the wandering monster, anyway?
Uh, well... that'd be...
If Lady Roxy joins the hunt... and sees me...
This place is kind of a dump!
Welcome.
I guess it'll do!
Traveling warriors?
Food and drinks for each of us, if you would.
Coming right up.
And on top of that...
Hey, missy.
Me?
Yeah.
Come on over and have some fun with us!
Stop!
What the hell do you think you're doing?!
Don't!
Only a holy knight could
pull a move like that!
A holy knight?!
Wha...
Lady Roxy?
Yeah, I figured.
Forgive me for the deception.
Roxy?!
From the Hart family?
One of the five families
supporting the king...
You're Roxy Hart?!
F-Forgive our trespass, milady!
S-Spare us our lives...
Y-You can have our money...
Put that away.
The fact that the people we are sworn
to protect view us as objects of fear
is something I deeply regret.
And... am shamed by.
Holy knights exist to protect the people.
A world where we could laugh
aside the kingdom's subjects...
That was my father's dream.
A dream I share.
She's just like Sir Mason.
And until that dream comes true...
Hey, mind if we chat with you?
I will follow Lady Roxy.
Come on, man!
Oh yeah, that's the spot
right there. Very, very nice...
That should do it.
Fantastic!
I feel like a new sword!
Thanks to your help, I got to take care
of some long-overdue maintenance.
I should be the one to thank you.
I was able to learn more about
the wandering monster thanks to you, Fate.
Come to think of it,
why didn't you know about the hunt?
The Vlerick family is heading up the effort
and didn't deign to inform me.
Them again...
Take your filthy hands off me!
Ow!
That voice...
It's Hado.
That hurts! Stop it!
What do you think you're doing?
Hado, release him!
You again?
We're just taking a lost child
into our protection.
You're a part of this, too, Memil?
And how is this protection?
Fay.
Ow! You son of a...
You seem to be doing well, Fate.
I'll see to the boy from here on.
Rafael, I must ask,
why did you not inform me about
the hunt for the wandering monster?
I'd assumed you'd be occupied with
thoughts of your departed father.
I am quite all right.
Good to know. If you'll excuse us...
You should act like the trash you are!
What's that look for?
Drop it, Hado. Come along.
I hate those stupid holy knights!
I am so sorry.
Why are you apologizing, miss?
Oh, you must not have
noticed in these clothes.
Did you get lost?
Yeah. I can't find my Mom.
Okay, the two of us will help you find her.
Okay!
I remember getting lost before, too.
It was after Dad died,
and I moved to the capital...
That'd be five years ago.
I wonder what happened to the holy
knight who looked after me back then.
I don't know if we can
keep looking for her today.
Mom...
Come now, don't cry.
You can stay at my house tonight,
and we'll look again tomorrow.
Leo?
Leo!
Mom!
I'm glad we were able to find her.
Is something the matter?
Uh, no, nothing!
I was just... thinking we'd better
get back soon or we'll get in trouble.
Fay...
Yes?
When we get in trouble...
we do it together, okay?
Understood! I'll be with you!
Very good.
Let's head back home, then.
Home...
Yes, Lady Roxy!
I hope days like this will last forever.
But...
What? A way to hunt monsters
without Roxy finding out?
Yeah. Do you have any ideas?
One thing comes to mind.
A perception warping magic item?
This mask will make us look
different to whoever sees us.
That's perfect! Okay...
This is for me?
My thanks for giving me this job.
It's because of you that
I have a new job, warm meals...
And friends that
I consider to be family now.
I'm truly grateful.
Fay... I understand, and I accept.
I was hoping to get the gem
you were looking at, but...
That's all right. I'm quite happy.
This power really is handy.
Fay! Look at this!
Fate, you cheater.
Be quiet!
Beautiful...
I'll treasure it.
I'm glad you like it.
What would you like in return?
You seem to love meat...
perhaps a year's supply?
Or maybe a whetstone
for sharpening your sword?
Oh, I like that!
I don't need anything in return!
That simply won't do.
One whetstone, then.
It's really okay!
Shut up, stupid! Accept the whetstone!
You better take better care of me!
I am telling you to be quiet!
We will now discuss the excursion to Galia...
Crowned Beast
"Crowned Beast."